All of a sudden,
so much is happening.
갑자기 너무 많은
사건이 일어났어
I know.
Ross is getting married.
그래, 로스는 결혼하고
피비는 인류를 생산 중이고
Phoebe's making people.
- 다들 뭔가를 하는데
- 우린 이게 뭐냐
-Everybody's doing stuff.
-We just sit here.
내가 이 세상에 다녀간 증거는
여기 남은 엉덩이 자국뿐이야
If I died,
people would know I was here...
...only by the ass print
on this chair!
-What are we doing?
-Wasting our lives.
- 지금 뭘 하는 걸까
- 인생을 낭비하고 있지
I meant for lunch.
점심 안 먹냐고
We have to do something.
Something huge!
우리도 뭐든 하자
뭔가 대단한 걸로
We could climb Mt. Everest.
에베레스트를 정복하자
Not something stupid.
Something huge!
푼수 짓이 아니라
큰일을 해보자고
I saw an ad for this video.
아냐, 비디오 광고를 봤거든
다들 하는데 우리라고 못하냐?
People climb that thing every day.
We could totally do that!
Why not?
I mean, it's just climbing.
맞아, 그래봤자 등산인데
-It's just steep!
-Yeah.
- 좀 높아서 그렇지
- 그럼
We're going! It'd be nice
to leave an ass print on Everest.
에베레스트 정상에다가
엉덩이 도장 찍고 오자
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
-We're gonna climb Mt. Everest.
-Yeah, baby!
- 에베레스트에 가려고
- 개봉박두!
진짜?
I looked into that.
나도 가보고 싶었지만
Yeah, but it costs like $60,000,
and, you know, you could die.
비용이 6만 달러에다
죽을 수도 있거든
그리고...
너흰 분명히 죽어
And you would die.
이런...
We could get that Everest video.
에베레스트 비디오나 보자
We could do that
without risking our lives at all.
그럼 죽을 위험도 전혀 없잖아
While we're at the video store,
we could rent Die Hard!
비디오가게 가면 잊지 말고
꼭 빌려오자, 다이하드!
I just remembered.
참, 그걸 잊고 있었네
That Everest thing is only available
through mail order.
그 에베레스트 비디오는
통신판매만 가능하대
나 참...
So you'll stay here
and hang out with me?
그럼 여기서 나랑
계속 놀 거지?
- 별수 있나
- 그래야지 뭐
But one of these days...
하지만 우린 조만간 밖에 나가
다이하드를 빌려오고 말겠어
...we'll get off our butts
and rent Die Hard again!
The One with the lnvitation
That was fast. It usually takes me
hours to get Ben to go down for his nap.
와! 벌써 끝났어? 난 저 녀석
재우려면 두어 시간 걸리는데
He's such a sweetheart.
Do you know what he said?
- 방금 뭐라고 한지 알아?
- 뭐랬는데?
-Good night, mommy.
-That's because he has lots of mommies.
'잘 자요, 엄마'
원래 녀석한테는
엄마가 많으니까
Yeah, in fact, it's kind of become
his word for "woman".
이젠 여자를 뜻하는
단어가 됐지
So does your uncle Nathan
get an invite or not?
결혼식에 네이선 삼촌
초대하기로 했던가?
Oh, God!
Nobody likes him.
그 삼촌은 다들 싫어해
He's so cheap. He'd never fly
to London in a million years.
말도 못할 자린고비라 하늘이
두 쪽 나도 런던엔 안 오실 걸?
Invite him!
그래, 초대해
이 정도면 깨끗하게 썼지?
Did I do these neat enough?
Yeah, they're fine.
- 그래, 괜찮네
- 그렇지?
We'll say that Ben addressed them.
누가 물어보면
벤이 썼다고 하지 뭐
You invited Rachel then?
- 오, 레이첼도 초대했네?
- 왜, 안돼?
Sure, why not?
Really?
- 진심이야?
- 그럼
I wouldn't be comfortable having
any of my old lovers there.
난 옛날애인이 식장에
나타나면 불편할 텐데
Do you think
we shouldn't invite her?
초대하지 말자는 거야?
You know I absolutely adore Rachel.
아냐, 나도 레이첼
좋아하는데 다만...
It's just that I thought
it might be awkward for you.
자기가 불편할까 봐 그러지
But it's absolutely your decision.
어쨌든 자기가 결정할 일이야
-More tea?
-Sure.
- 차 더 할래?
- 그러지 뭐
Earl Grey?
얼 그레이 홍차?
Fine, invite whoever you want.
어? 그래, 좋아
누구든 초대해
난 혼자 사는 거 싫어
다시 결혼하고 싶다니까
I don't want to be single, okay?
I just want to be married again.
전 백만 달러만 주세요!
And I just want a million dollars!
레이첼?
Oh God, Monica. Thank God!
세상에, 모니카
정말 반갑다
다들 인사해, 얘는 레이첼이야
링컨 고교의 또 다른 생존자지
This is Rachel.
Another Lincoln High survivor.
This is Chandler.
이쪽은 내 친구들
챈들러, 피비, 조이...
Phoebe.
Joey.
우리 오빠 로스는 알지?
-Do you remember Ross?
-Sure.
- 그럼
- 안녕
Back in high school...
잘 몰랐겠지만 고등학교 때
너 때문에 애 많이 태웠거든
...I had a major crush on you.
I knew.
- 알고 있었어
- 그랬구나
You did?
I figured you thought
I was Monica's geeky brother.
모니카의 얼간이 오빠로만
생각하는 줄 알았는데
I did.
- 그랬어
- 오!
Listen, do you think
궁금한 게 있는데...
Try not to let my intense
vulnerability become a factor.
난 쉽게 상처를 받지만
부담 가질 건 없고
내가 가끔 데이트
신청하면 받아줄래?
Would it be okay
if I asked you out sometime?
그래
Maybe.
봐서
좋아
Okay, maybe I will.
그럼 봐서 신청할게
See, I see...
열정적인 사랑이
널 기다리고 있어
...big passion in your future.
-Really?
-I do.
- 정말?
- 그럼
Ross, you're so great.
로스, 정말 고마워
It's never gonna happen.
애시당초 꿈 깨라
I have a question.
질문 하나 할까?
Actually, it's not
so much a question.
사실 질문이라기보다는
궁금한 거라고 해야겠다
It's more of a general wondering...
...ment.
궁금증
- 말해봐
- 좋아
난 사실 그동안 줄곧...
Well, for a while now,
I've been wanting to....
- 오...
- 그래
Yes, yes.
- 바로 그거야
- 저 앙증맞은 고양이!
That's right.
Look!
What?
뭐?
Top of the world looking
Down on creation
And the only explanation I can find
이 카트 가져갈 거면
나도 같이 끌고 가요!
Listen, missy! If you want this cart,
you'll have to take me with it!
만세, 봤지?
-Did you see that?
-You were incredible!
- 대단했어
- 나 잘했지?
A brand-new woman,
ladies and gentlemen.
방금 출시된 신여성입니다
- 나 혼자선 못해냈을 거야
- 어, 그래...
I could not have done this
without you.
저기, 엄...
More clothes in the dryer?
건조기에 빨래 더 있지?
괜찮아
I'm fine.
내게 좋은 감정이
있었다고 말하지 마
You had no right to tell me
you had feelings for me.
뭐?
그전까진 줄리하고
잘 지내왔어
I was doing great with Julie
before I found out.
나도 그전까진 잘 지내왔어
너희들 보는 게 편한 줄 알아?
I was doing great too. It's not
easy for me to see you with Julie.
하여튼 난 지금
이런 거 필요 없어
I don't need this right now.
It's too late.
이젠 너무 늦었다고
I'm with somebody else.
This ship has sailed!
난 다른 사람이 있고 행복해
이 버스는 벌써 떠났어
All right, fine!
Go ahead and do that.
- 좋아, 가던 길 열심히 가
- 염려 붙들어 매셔
그런 똥차는 나도 안 타
I don't need your stupid ship!
- 좋아
- 그래
This is the first time I'm doing
something I care about.
처음으로 내가 좋아하는
일을 찾았다는 거 몰라?
I'm doing something
that I'm actually good at.
생전 처음으로 내가
잘하는 일을 찾았어
If you don't get that
- 이해를 못하나본데...
- 충분히 이해해
I get that, but I'm tired
of your answering machine.
십분 이해하고 나도 기쁘지만
자동응답기랑 사귈 순 없어
I don't know what to do.
- 날더러 어떡하라고
- 그럼 난!
Neither do l!
Is this about Mark?
마크 때문인가?
Oh, my God!
세상에
- 아니면 말고
- 기가 막혀
Okay, it's not.
똑같은 싸움을 또 하고 또 하고
사람을 왜 이렇게 힘들게 하지?
I can't keep having this
same fight over and over again.
You're making this too hard!
내가 힘들게 만드나?
그럼 어떻게 해줄까
I am?
What do you want me to do?
나도 모르겠어
잠시 냉각기를 갖자
I don't know. Look, maybe
we should just take a break.
맞아, 열 좀 식히는 거야
냉동요구르트나 먹자고
You're right. Let's cool off.
Let's get some frozen yogurt
or something.
아니
A break from us.
우리 당분간 헤어져
-Why are we rushing?
-The girlfriend I told you about.
왜 그렇게 서둘러요?
간밤에 얘기했던 내
여자친구가 말이죠...
She wants to get back
together with me.
나랑 다시 만나재요
야호, 찾았다!
I found it!
That's so great for you guys!
- 정말 잘됐네요
- 그래요
-Good luck with your girlfriend.
-Thank you.
- 잘되길 빌어요
- 고마워요, 아서라...
레이첼!
- 내 메시지 받았어?
- 그럼, 시간 딱 맞췄네
-You got my message?
-You are right on time.
Can I be your girlfriend again?
어떻게 생각해?
다시 시작할 수 있어?
You can very much.
그럼, 물론이지
당장 여기서 나가
I want you to leave.
Get out!
싫어, 있어야겠어
얘기 마저 끝내
I want to talk about this.
그래, 좋아
그 여자 어땠어?
All right, how was she?
어어?
-What?
-Was she good?
뭐?
- 그 여자 괜찮았어?
- 그 답변은 피해라
Don't answer!
You wanted to talk about it.
How was she?
뭐해, 얘기하자며?
그 여자 어땠냐고
She was....
그 여잔...
- 끔찍했어, 너랑 비교도 안돼
- 별로였어, 밥맛이야
-She was not good, not good.
-Nothing compared to you.
She was different.
그 여잔 달랐어
- 으이구!
- 어어...
Good different?
좋은 쪽으로 달랐어?
Nobody likes change.
누가 변화를 좋아하나
Just stop!
닥쳐, 망할 놈아
The way you owned up to everything.
자기 행동을 보니까
철이 많이 든 것 같아
It's just showed me
how much you've grown, you know?
I mean, my mom never thought
this would work out.
엄마는 절대
안 될 거라고 했지
She was all,
"Once a cheater, always a cheater."
'한 번 바람둥이는
영원한 바람둥이야'
I just wish we hadn't lost
those four months.
넉 달을 허송세월했어
But if time was what you needed
just to gain a little perspective.
그 동안 보는 눈이 좀
넓어졌다니 다행이지만
We were on a break!
우린 그때 깨진 상태였어!
수신 : 레이첼 그린
- 진심으로 좋아하잖아
- 그래, 맞아
You seem to really like her.
What do I do?
We agreed it'd be a two-week thing.
하지만 어쩔 거야, 둘 다
2주라는 시간에 동의했는데
No commitment.
구속은 없어
로스?
That girl just spent the entire evening
talking to your friends...
에밀리는 저녁 내내
네 친구들과 얘기하고
...asking to hear stories about you...
너에 대해서 물어보고
모니카의 사진첩을 봤어
...Iooking through
Monica's photo albums.
You don't do that
if you're just in it for two weeks.
2주 사귀고 끝낼
사람이 그러나?
You think?
정말?
에밀리가 공항에 가려면
아직 14시간이나 남았는데
You've got 14 hours until
she has to be at the airport.
And you're sitting here
in a hallway...
복도에서 입술 부은 28살 짜리
치어리더랑 청승만 떨 거야?
...with a 28-year-old cheerleader
with a fat lip.
-You're right.
-Yeah.
- 네 말이 맞아
- 그럼
정말 근사하다
This is so amazing!
My brother's getting married
and in London!
오빠가 런던에서 결혼하다니
너무 낭만적이야
It's so romantic.
Hey, pretty smart!
야, 머리 잘 썼는데?
티슈 화장지잖아
Tissue paper.
You're at the wedding.
You have to cry.
식장에서 눈물이 나면?
Handkerchief?
No, I got my invitation.
손수건? 아니, 청첩장이 있어
Isn't this adorable?
글씨 너무 귀엽다
벤 시켜서 썼나봐
Ross let Ben address mine.
- 안녕
- 어서 와
Did you get your invitation
to Ross' wedding?
로스 청첩장 받았어?
No.
아니?
Don't worry, I get to bring a guest.
We'll show him.
걱정 말고 나만 따라오면 돼
I'm so jealous you're all going.
나만 빼고 다 가네, 만삭 때
비행기 타면 안 되는 거였어?
I never knew you can't fly
in your third trimester.
I didn't, either.
- 그러게
- 나도 몰랐어
I knew that.
난 알았는데
So I didn't know that.
But you should see your faces.
그래, 몰랐다
표정 가관이네
What's up?
얘들아, 뭐해?
- 너 왔구나
- 그냥 놀아
Just hanging out.
What's this?
Ross' wedding invitation?
이게 뭐지?
로스 청첩장이야?
Maybe that's the one
we should have hidden.
숨기려면 저걸 숨겼어야지
No, you guys, come on.
You don't have to do that.
아냐, 왜들 이래
그럴 거 없어
나도 기쁜 걸
I'm happy for him.
I am. I really
정말이라니까
난 진짜... 괜찮을 거야
I'll work on it.
I'm sorry.
어떡하니
You're going to come, though,
aren't you?
그래도 참석은 할 거지?
글쎄, 모르겠다
I don't know.
그렇다고 우리까지 못 가는 건
아니겠지? 난 티켓도 사놨고...
This isn't one of those
"lf she doesn't come, we don't come"?
-I bought my ticket.
-You're not even invited.
너 청첩장 받았냐?
You know what would be real weird?
If you weren't there.
네가 안 가면
더 이상할 거야
-Just say you'll think about it.
-I'll think about it.
- 다시 생각해봐
- 그래, 알았어
-Who's this from?
-That's Ross'.
- 이건 누구 거지?
- 로스가 준비한 거야
Oh, my God!
세상에
He remembered.
기억하고 있었어
Remembered what?
뭘 기억해?
It was months ago.
We were walking by this antique store.
몇 달 전에 로스하고
골동품상 옆을 지나다
I saw this and told him
it was like one my grandmother had...
이게 옛날 우리 할머니 거랑
똑같다고 한 적이 있거든
...when I was a little girl.
I can't believe he remembered!
그걸 기억하고 있었다니
This must've cost a fortune.
꽤 줬겠다
I can't believe he did this.
오빠한테 이런 면이 있었나?
대학 때 캐롤한테 빠졌을 때도
무지 비싼 수정 오리를 사줬어
Remember when he fell in love
with Carol...
...and got her
that expensive crystal duck?
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
그게 머시기냐...
Oh, my God!
이런 맙소사
Flight number 457
from Beijing now arriving.
베이징 발 457편이
도착했습니다
Oh, my God!
저게 뭐야
-We were in school together.
-We haven't seen each other since.
- 우린 대학원 동기예요
- 졸업하고는 못 봤는데
I land in China.
Guess who's in charge of the dig?
중국에 갔더니 발굴책임자가
누구였는지 알아?
Julie!
줄리!
Isn't that great?
기막힌 인연이네요
Isn't that just kick-you-in-the-crotch,
spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
복날에 게거품 물고
팔짝 뛰게 기막혀요
에이, 낯간지럽게...
That is so sweet!
아냐
아니, 자기가 먼저 끊어
No, you hang up.
No, you
싫어, 자기가...
좋아, 그럼...
One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋...
You didn't hang up!
- 자기도 안 끊었잖아
- 그래, 안 끊었구나
She didn't hang up either.
Okay, no. No, you hang up.
좋아, 아냐
먼저 끊어
You!
자기 먼저! 자기 먼저! 자기...
Ross, hi.
로스, 나야
레이첼이라고
It's Rachel.
I'm just calling to say
that everything's fine.
이 말하려고 전화했어
모든 게 잘 풀렸다고
And I'm really happy for you...
행복하다니 나도 기뻐
고양이랑 잘 살아라
...and your cat.
우리 완전히 끝난 것 같다
Obviously, I am over you.
I am over you.
이걸로 끝내겠어
And that, my friend,
is what they call closure.
굳이 내 친구 말을
빌리자면 '종쳤다'
I got a message from you.
네가 보낸 메시지야
Oh, my God!
Hang up the phone!
맙소사, 안돼, 끊어
이리 내놔! 내놔! 내놔!
Give me the phone!
달라니까...
You're over me?
나랑 끝낸다고?
Oh, God.
난 몰라
- 나하고...
- 이런...
You're over me?
- 끝낸다 이거야?
- 어쩜 좋아
언제 너부터...
When were you...
...under me?
시작했었냐?
Basically...
얘기하자면...
요즘 들어서...
...Iately, I've....
너한테 야릇한 감정이 생겼어
I've sort of had feelings for you.
I need to lie down.
나 좀 누울게
He broke up with Julie!
줄리랑 끝났대
Go hug her, for God's sakes!
어서 가서 안아줘
-Really?
-Really.
- 진짜야?
- 그래
난 역시 너밖에 없어
It's always been you, Rach.
Oh, God.
세상에...
Listen, I'm sorry
I had to work tonight.
미안해, 오늘 야근이야
괜찮아, 얼마든지 기다릴게
That's okay.
You're worth the wait.
And I don't just mean tonight.
언제까지 기다릴 수 있어
아! 엄마야!
Oh, God!
Honey.
자기야, 난 괜찮아
That's okay.
No, you just rolled over
the juice box.
아니, 주스 팩이 터진 거야
Did you say anything to Rachel about
me and the girl from the copy place?
건터, 레이첼한테 복사가게
아가씨 얘기한 건 아니죠?
I'm sorry.
미안해, 말하면
안 되는 거였어?
Was I not supposed to?
끝내자고 한 건 너야
You ended it!
화가 나서 그런 거지
사랑하지 않아서가 아냐
Because I was mad at you.
Not because I stopped loving you.
You still love me?
- 아직 날 사랑하니?
- 아니
What does this mean?
Do you want to get back together?
그게 무슨 뜻이야, 혹시...
- 옛날로 돌아가고 싶어?
- 아니, 어쩌면
Maybe.
- 글쎄, 난...
- 뭐야
I don't know.
I just, I feel....
난 그냥...
다시 합칠 생각을 하다니
내가 미쳤지, 진짜 끝이야
I can't believe I even thought of
getting back together. We're so over!
Fine by me!
좋시다!
And hey! Just so you know,
it's not that common.
그게 아무 남자한테나 생기는
복인 줄 아나 본데 정신 차려!
It doesn't happen to every guy,
and it is a big deal.
I knew it!
그렇다니까!
Rachel's coming up.
Doesn't she look pretty?
레이첼이 왔어요
정말 예쁘죠, 여보?
Oh, my God!
맙소사
뭔지 알겠어?
졸업무도회 날이야
This is us getting ready
for the prom.
We don't have to watch this.
저런 걸 뭐 하러 봐
- 왜, 재미있겠는데
- 그래, 한번 보자
Yeah, we do!
Come on!
- 모니카도 찍어줘요
- 줌아웃은 어떻게 하지?
-Get a shot of Monica.
-How do you zoom out?
There she is!
이제 보인다
Shut up!
The camera adds 10 pounds.
됐어, 카메라에 찍히면
5킬로는 더 나가 보여
카메라 몇 대로 찍었는데
So how many cameras
are actually on you?
Dad, turn it off!
아빠, 끄세요!
꺼진 거야
그렇지, 로스?
It is off.
Right, Ross?
Looking good, Mr. Kotter!
멋있는데, 코털선생?
I can't go to my prom without a date.
It's too late.
파트너도 없이 무도회에
어떻게 가, 이젠 늦었어
If you're not going,
then I don't want to go either.
너 안 가면 나도 안 갈래
I have a wonderful idea.
좋은 생각이 있다
네가 레이첼을 데려가라
You should take Rachel to the prom.
- 이제 다 봤으면 끄자
- 왜 그래, 그냥 둬
We've seen enough.
Let's turn it off.
-I want to see!
-Fine, I'm not going to watch.
좋아, 난 안 볼래
Come on, kid. Let's go.
자, 어서 나오너라
Are you handsome!
너무 근사하구나
Let's show them!
가서 보여줘
-Okay, Dad.
-Rachel, ready or not.
- 됐어요, 아버지
- 레이첼, 준비됐니?
Here comes your knight in shining
너의 멋진 기사님이...
오, 이런
- 다녀올게요, 아빠
- 안녕히 계세요
Oh, dear!
이 일을 어쩌나
여보, 이거 좀 꺼요
How do I turn this off?
I can't believe you did that.
저런 일이 있었어?
Yeah, well....
그래...
봤지? 로스는 쟤 밥이야
See? He's her lobster!
No.
안돼
You're really not going?
- 진짜 안 갈 거야?
- 그래
It's just going to be too hard.
너무 힘들 것 같아
You know, I mean...
다른 사람도 아니고...
로스잖아
...it's Ross.
How can I watch him get married?
로스 결혼하는 걸 어떻게 봐
It's just for the best.
You know? It is.
이게 최선의 방법이야
Plus somebody's got
to stay here with Phoebe.
피비 곁에도 누가 있어줘야지
She's going to be pretty big by then.
이제 배가 더 불러올 텐데
She'll need someone
to help her tie her shoes.
신발 끈 매는 것도 도와주고
Drive her to the hospital
if she goes into labor.
진통하면 병원에도 데려가고
You don't have a car.
넌 차도 없잖아
면허도 취소됐고
And your license expired.
알아, 할 일은 많은데
시간은 없잖아
There's so much to do,
and I have so little time!
Check this out.
이것 좀 봐, 박물관 비디오를
다 구비해놓은 가게가 있는데
There's a place you can go
to rent videos of all the museums.
"It's almost as good as being there."
가서 보는 거나 매한가지래
It's better! You can't go to a museum
in your underwear.
훨 낫지, 속옷만 입고
박물관에 갈 수 있냐?
You could, but just the one time.
갈 수는 있지만
다시는 못 가겠지
We could get videos
of the sights...
관광명소 비디오도 있잖아
...get a VCR in our hotel room
and never have to go outside!
호텔 비디오로 보면
나다닐 필요도 없어
-lf we do that, we've got to rent Die Hard.
-I bet the British version is good!
그럼 다이하드 꼭 빌리자
오호, 영국판도 참신하지